<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kongesalen 1 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</title>
    <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kongesalen 1 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Working effectively with your working memory</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/working-effectively-with-your-working-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/working-effectively-with-your-working-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our ability to learn and work effectively with code depends on our ability to get concepts from the screen and into sensory memory, through working memory for processing, and then into long-term memory for storage. As the working memory is of quite limited capacity we must use it wisely, but there are strategies we can use to get more out of our limited brains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sommerstudenter - hvorfor gidde?</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/sommerstudenter-hvorfor-gidde/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/sommerstudenter-hvorfor-gidde/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sommerstudenter - hvorfor gidde?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Det har de siste par årene blitt en liten Booster-tradisjon å snakke om ferskingene: studentene og juniorene.&#xA;I keynotes, erfaringsrapporter og lyntaler har sommerjobber blitt forsvart fra juniorenes perspektiv, lenge før det ble et hett tema. Vi har utforsket hvilke fordeler og utfordringer som følger med å ha juniorer på teamet, og ikke minst hvilket ansvar bransjen har for å fostre neste generasjon utviklere og designere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make an internal conference worth our time</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/how-to-make-an-internal-conference-worth-our-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/how-to-make-an-internal-conference-worth-our-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Effective collaboration is vital in any forward-thinking organization, but it rarely can be established top-down. The developer community at Equinor took a bottom-up approach to make our annual internal conference consistently amazing, with 200 sign-ups within the first hour in 2024. As one of the organizers, I will share some secrets on how to &amp;ldquo;git commit&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;git merge&amp;rdquo; a conference that provides learning and reinforces the community.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inclusive Design: Creating User Experiences That Embrace Diversity</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/inclusive-design-creating-user-experiences-that-embrace-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/inclusive-design-creating-user-experiences-that-embrace-diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk explores inclusive design—a human-centered approach that goes beyond accessibility and universal design to create experiences that embrace the full diversity of human characteristics. Through real-world examples, it highlights the importance of designing for differences in ethnicity, gender, age, physical abilities, and socio-economic backgrounds, ensuring that digital and physical products foster inclusion and belonging for all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
