<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kongesalen 2-3 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</title>
    <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kongesalen 2-3 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ignite your creative spark: Toolkit for a creative mindset</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/ignite-your-creative-spark-toolkit-for-a-creative-mindset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/ignite-your-creative-spark-toolkit-for-a-creative-mindset/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone can be creative, we just need to learn how to facilitate it and use it. Harnessing creativity requires an awareness of how much your mindset, routines and habits can limit your creative potential, and what to do instead. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll share some of the most common pitfalls of the creative process, and some practical tips to overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven minute reflections – a team practice for increased learning</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/seven-minute-reflections-a-team-practice-for-increased-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/seven-minute-reflections-a-team-practice-for-increased-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This practice is something we stumbled upon, inspired by journaling, personal knowledge management (aka PKM) and Llewellyn Falco&amp;rsquo;s very efficient &amp;ldquo;observation retrospectives&amp;rdquo;. We tried this in a team and it had some interesting effects. Then we tried it in some more settings and people enjoyed it. Now we just have to share it with the Booster attendees!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unseen, Unheard, Unaccounted: Addressing the Gender Data Gap&#39;s Impact on Women</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/unseen-unheard-unaccounted-addressing-the-gender-data-gap-s-impact-on-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/unseen-unheard-unaccounted-addressing-the-gender-data-gap-s-impact-on-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where data drives decisions, the absence of gender-specific data has led to a significant bias against women. In this talk, we will look at how inadequate data representation leads to real-world impacts on our daily lives - from healthcare disparities to flawed AI algorithms. We will also discuss the importance of gender-specific data in creating inclusive systems and services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fra complianzzZz til bedre produkter!</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/fra-complianzzzz-til-bedre-produkter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/7_lightning_talks/kongesalen_2_3/fra-complianzzzz-til-bedre-produkter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Compliance blir ofte en plikt vi bare må gjennom før vi skal tilbake til den ekte produktutviklingen. Vi må tenke annerledes om det. Vi må ta perspektivet til produktteam og få compliance inn i den smidige læringssløyfen slik at de raskt finner ut av om det de gjør er OK. Først da er teamene trygge på hva de kan gjøre for å lære om brukernes behov og hvordan de kan løse disse best mulig. Og da lager vi bedre produkter drevet av god compliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
