<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kongesalen 2-3 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</title>
    <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/kongesalen_2_3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kongesalen 2-3 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/kongesalen_2_3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>World Beyond Summit – en metode for scenariobygging</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/kongesalen_2_3/world-beyond-summit-en-metode-for-scenariobygging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/kongesalen_2_3/world-beyond-summit-en-metode-for-scenariobygging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Verden forandrer seg raskt, og det er ikke alltid lett å vite hva som vil gjøre produktene våre relevante i fremtiden. Vi må slutte å spørre brukerne om hva som er fremtidens behov, men heller forstå mer hvordan større drivkrefter kan snu opp ned på hverdagen deres.&#xA;I dette foredraget viser jeg hvordan produktteam kan bruke scenariobygging for å navigere i usikkerhet og ta smartere valg. Jeg tar dere gjennom et konkret case som viser hvordan dette gjøres i praksis med eksempler på verktøy som vi har utviklet for scenariobygging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake it till you make it - a tale from two developers on their journey through imposter syndrome</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/kongesalen_2_3/fake-it-till-you-make-it-a-tale-from-two-developers-on-their-journey-through-imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/kongesalen_2_3/fake-it-till-you-make-it-a-tale-from-two-developers-on-their-journey-through-imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is the concept of «imposter syndrome” unfamiliar to you? Of course not! If you are a developer who haven’t heard of or felt the imposter syndrome then you are definitely the exception and not the rule. So how to overcome this obstacle, find the confidence in yourself and reach your potential? In this session you will hear from two people who have been in the industry for over 20 years. They will share their aspect both as developers and as females on how the imposter syndrome have affected them, what they have learnt and where the journey has taken them. (Note! This session will be held in Norwegian!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swipe left on Agile pitfalls so you can swipe right on DevOps!</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/kongesalen_2_3/swipe-left-on-agile-pitfalls-so-you-can-swipe-right-on-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/kongesalen_2_3/swipe-left-on-agile-pitfalls-so-you-can-swipe-right-on-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agile has been embraced by organizations worldwide to meet the dynamic market conditions and customer demands through iterative development and delivery.  At its core the Agile promise was better, more responsive and efficient ways to deliver software while maintaining a close connection with the customer and empowering teams to innovate and adapt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But there is an increasingly unsettling feeling in many teams and organizations and many are ready to swipe left on Agile due to the pitfalls and missteps on the way. But this is a goldmine that DevOps teams can learn from. In this talk, we will delve into how the overemphasis on processes, tools, metrics, events &amp;amp; high focus on speed of delivery has led to this situation and how DevOps teams can avoid getting burnt by similar pitfalls. We will talk about what really matters to rise above the theatrics to derive real value for your teams and organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
