<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</title>
    <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 09:40:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monetary policy</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/monetary-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 09:40:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/monetary-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Booster is a non-profit conference, run by a group of volunteers. Our goal is to create the best possible conference&#xA;for our participants and speakers, and to strengthen the local software development community.&#xA;Any profits from the conference are used to ensure that we can continue organizing the conference in the following&#xA;years. We are normally not able to cover travel and lodging for speakers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are quite a few exceptions though. We invite a limited number of speakers in order to ensure diversity,&#xA;and to help market the conference for both submissions and early bird ticket sales. For invited speakers, we refund&#xA;reasonable travel expenses and provide hotel. We do not pay honorariums for any speakers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partner with Booster</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/become-a-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 09:40:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/become-a-partner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Booster is an international IT conference situated in Bergen, and the most important meeting place for the local software development community. Booster is a forum for presentation, debate and study of information technology and agile methods, organized as a three day conference with lectures, workshops and lightning talks of high academic quality.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Booster is aimed at software developers, project managers, testers, designers, architects, security experts and usability professionals. Booster focuses on craftsmanship, methods and quality and facilitates for professional networking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Booster Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/coc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 17:36:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/coc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All attendees, speakers, partners, staff and volunteers at our conference are required to follow the code of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;short-version&#34;&gt;Short Version&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have a good time and help others have a good time too. Say hi to someone you don’t know. Meet interesting people. Don’t act surprised when a person doesn’t conform to a stereotype. No one is at Booster just to represent a minority so start conversations about tech, the weather, the food, the best speaker or the delights of Bergen before talking about “being minority X in tech”. Make sure people are okay with touching before you touch them. Laugh and learn. You, and everyone else, is here to have a good time and learn something new – &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/about/#organizers&#34;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt; if anything is getting in the way of that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What makes Booster special?</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 17:36:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Booster is a software conference for the entire team. That means if you’re a developer, project manager, architect, UX professional, tester or security professional, we have something for you!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our goal is that you come back from the conference with real knowledge you can use. That’s why interactive, hands-on workshops fill up most of the hours of the conference. We also have lightning talks, a few short talks, a couple of keynotes and open spaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Booster Kids</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For åttende gang arrangerer Boosterkonferansen, i samarbeid med Bergen Offentlige Bibliotek, utviklerkonferanse for barn.&#xA;Konferansen avholdes på Radisson Blu Royal Hotel, Bryggen 30. mars 2025.&#xA;Det blir kurs for ulike aldersgrupper og et sterkt faglig innhold, akkurat slik en god konferanse skal være!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OBS: Foreldre trenger ikke å booke billetter til seg selv!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;program&#34;&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;11:00-12:00: Registrering&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;12:00-13:30: Workshops, del 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13:30-14:15: Lunsj&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;14:15-16:00: Workshops, del 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;16:00: Takk for i år!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merk: Programmet kan endres fortløpende&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Booster Kids Early Access</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/partners-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/info/partners-kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For åttende gang arrangerer Boosterkonferansen, i samarbeid med Bergen Offentlige Bibliotek, utviklerkonferanse for barn.&#xA;Konferansen avholdes på Radisson Blu Royal Hotel, Bryggen 30. mars 2025.&#xA;Det blir kurs for ulike aldersgrupper og et sterkt faglig innhold, akkurat slik en god konferanse skal være!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OBS: Foreldre trenger ikke å booke billetter til seg selv!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;program&#34;&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11:00 - 12:00:&lt;/strong&gt; Registrering&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12:00 - 13:30:&lt;/strong&gt; Workshops, del 1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13:30 - 14:15:&lt;/strong&gt; Lunsj&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14:15 - 16:00:&lt;/strong&gt; Workshops, del 2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
