<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kongesalen 1 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</title>
    <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kongesalen 1 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Speaking Your Mind: The Why and Where and When and What and How</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/speaking-your-mind-the-why-and-where-and-when-and-what-and-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/speaking-your-mind-the-why-and-where-and-when-and-what-and-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a survey performed by NRK in 2023 36% of people in Norway choose to withhold their opinions because they are afraid of the response.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can we, as IT professionals, make sure that our spaces are safe to participate in and engage with? How do we make sure that both junior and senior colleagues feel free enough to express their professional opinions, while allowing them to be themselves in the process?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hvordan kommunisere godt – 9 prinsipper som er nyttige for alle</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/hvordan-kommunisere-godt-9-prinsipper-som-er-nyttige-for-alle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/hvordan-kommunisere-godt-9-prinsipper-som-er-nyttige-for-alle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;God kommunikasjon reduserer misforståelser, sparer tid og bygger tillit. I dette foredraget lærer du hvordan du ved hjelp av klarspråk kan gjøre budskapet ditt så tydelig som mulig, uansett hvem du er og hvem du kommuniserer med. Dette foredraget passer for alle – enten du er utvikler, teamlead eller designer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The power of a story!</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/the-power-of-a-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/the-power-of-a-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This talk will inspire you to use strategic storytelling as a tool to achieve a desired outcome. You will be introduced to a simple model by McKee &amp;amp; Gerace (2018) which you can use to structure your next story in an engaging and convincing way. You will be introduced to heroes, villains, obstacles, and allies and learn how the characters and the plot will create a story that will capture the audience&amp;rsquo;s attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organizing your week as a developer or tech lead</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/organizing-your-week-as-a-developer-or-tech-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/wednesday/5_lightning_talks/kongesalen_1/organizing-your-week-as-a-developer-or-tech-lead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt stressed about priorities, tasks you might have forgotten or missed, things you’re unsure how to handle, or how much time they might take?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Productivity is a science of its own, but we’ll explore some tips and tricks on how to organize your month, week, and day to minimize anxiety and make the most of your time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
