<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dreggen 3 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</title>
    <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/dreggen_3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dreggen 3 on Booster Conference 2025 Bergen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/dreggen_3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From zero to your own blog</title>
      <link>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/dreggen_3/from-zero-to-your-own-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.boosterconf.no/2025/program/friday/1_short_talks_and_workshops/dreggen_3/from-zero-to-your-own-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you often thought that you want to write more? That you should dust off an old blog or set up a new one? Or that writing is hard and you don’t know how to start? This is the opportunity you have been waiting for!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This workshop is for anyone who wants to kick-start a new writing habit — and to get a site of their own with blog posts in Markdown. We will set up a minimal project with static site generator Eleventy that publishes to GitHub Pages. I have different approaches depending on your background, and you do not need to be a developer. Technical requirements are a laptop and a GitHub account. If you are a person who wants to run a local development server with Node.js and you prefer to procrastinate on any actual writing by tweaking the configuration and the code of your new site, this can also be what you do during this workshop. But the rest of us… we will help each other brainstorm ideas for topics, practice making shitty first drafts, and motivate each other to turn drafts into published posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
